Guide to the Syria Collection of photographs AD.MC.036
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Syria Collection
1940s-1980s
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Nikolskaya, Xenia
A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beyrouth (Beirut, Lebanon)
Above Cinema Mounir, Syria
Al Douli International Studio, Damascus (Syria)
Ali Baba, Syria
Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]
Apamis, Aleppo, Syria
C. Almas [?], Damascus, [Syria]
Cairo Studio, Ahmed Hariri, Damascus, [Syria]
Hassen Yazil, Syria
Issa Freres, Beyrouth (Beirut, Lebanon)
Photo Boyadjian, 65 Avenue Barada, Damascus, Syria
Photo Cine Azad, Damascus, [Syria]
Photo J. Gazarian, Bab Touma, Damascus, Syria
Photo Katchadour, Damascus, [Syria]
Photo Kermanik, Syria
Photo Rapide, Grand Hotel Bloudan, Semerjdian Frères, [Syria]
Photo V. Derounian, Aleppo, Syria
Qusai, Aleppo, Syria
Rahe, Syria
Reem Color, Damascus, Syria
Sadek Qassees, Damascus, Syria
Samir Color Lab, Saudi Arabia
Sarkissian Studio, Damascus, Syria
Sons et Couleurs (Beirut, Lebanon)
Abdel Nour, Damascus, (Syria)
Studio Al Ahram, Aleppo, (Syria)
Photo Al Andalous, Syria
Studio Al Assime, (Syria)
Studio Al Khayyam, Damascus, Syria
Studio Al Sabah, Damascus, (Syria)
Studio Al-Babk, Damascus, (Syria)
Studio Al-Kindi, Syria
Studio Al-Rabih, (Syria)
Studio Alsabah, Damascus, Syria
Studio Antoin, Damascus, Syria
Studio Carmen, Damascus, Syria
Studio Dikran, Damascus, (Syria)
Dunia, Derhagopian, Rue Fouad, 1er, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Echbelia, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Egypt, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria)
Garbis, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Georges Derzi, Press Photography Department, Salhieh, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Hadad, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Haig, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Housam (Syria)
Studio Hovnan, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Karwan (Syria)
Studio Khallaf, Syria
Studio Le Caire, Rue Fardos, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Manuel A&P (Syria)
Studio Minas (Chouhada, Salhiyeh, Damascus, Syria)
Studio Mesmar, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Photo Monsour, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Najah, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Najah (Syria)
Studio Omayad, Rue Fardosse, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Rateb, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Safar & Vartan, Rue Fardosse, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Safar, Sanjakdar, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Sameer, Damascus (Syria)
Studio Suri Ramis (Syria)
Studio Tuni and Safar, Entree de Rue Fardoss, Côté de Tour D'Argent, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Vense, Zahlé (Lebanon)
Studio Wacim, Abou Roumaneh, Rue Miseloun, Damascus (Syria)
Yazouy (Syria)
Studio Zaven, Aleppo (Syria)
Studio Zenobia, (Syria)
Studio el Seyahe, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Tirage Photo Dadour, Alep (Aleppo, Syria)
Yacoub Touranian, Jordan
AD.MC.036
9 paige_boxes 1,255 photographs and 25 negatives in 8 boxes and 1 oversized flat box.
Acquired from photographer Xenia Nikolskaya and researcher Heba Habib, the Syria Collection includes 1281 photographs including black and white gelatin silver prints and color photographs. The images document the social and cultural life of Syria from the 1940's to the 1980's. They portray religious ceremonies, daily life, street scenes of Damascus, archaeological sites, schools, picnics, family trips, costume parties, historic sites, and landscapes.
Box 1 - 9
Arrangement
Organized into ten series according to the order in which the materials were received from the donor.
The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Marie Rose Krikorian Series - Box: 5; Box: 9 Adel Bassem Series Studio Portraits Amphitheater Series - Box: 4 Actor Headshots Series Series - Box: 5 Party Series Series - Box: 5 Aleppo Series Series - Box: 6 Studio Series II Series - Box: 7 Studio Series III Series - Box: 8 Wedding Portrait Series
Scope and Contents
Acquired from photographer Xenia Nikolskaya and researcher Heba Habib, the Syria Collection includes 1,255 photographs including black and white gelatin silver prints and color photographs, as well as 25 negatives. The images document the social and cultural life of Syria from the 1940's to the 1980's. They portray religious ceremonies, daily life, street scenes of Damascus, archaeological sites, schools, picnics, family trips, costume parties, historic sites, and landscapes. There are also 10 photographs taken in Lebanon.
Biographical / Historical
.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All images acquired from Xenia Nikolskaya in 2018.
Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Sports; Nikolskaya, Xenia
- Marie Rose Krikorian Series (Box 5, Box 9, Box 1)
  - A portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian in front of a door., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 13.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Hats; Individual Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (right) with a woman., Circa 1940-1960; 13.4 x 8.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photographic Prints; Syria; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Jewelry
  - A portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian. (link ref1, 4)., 1940-1960; 9 x 13.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian (link ref 1, 3)., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photographic Prints; Hats; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Syria
  - A studio portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian wearing a head cover., Circa 1940-1960; 18 x 11.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Studio Photography; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A studio portrait of Jareh Krikorian wearing a striped tie., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Dikran, Damascus, (Syria); 17.5 x 11.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Damascus, Syria; Men; Signatures; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A studio portrait of Jareh Krikorian wearing a striped tie (linked ref6)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Dikran, Damascus, (Syria); 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Damascus, Syria; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Signatures; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men
  - A portrait of a woman sitting next to a "PFAFF" sewing machine. (link ref9, 10)., Circa 1950-1965; 13 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Furnishings; Sewing; Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A portrait of a woman standing in front of a large sewing machine. (link ref8, 10)., Circa 1950-1965; 13.1 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Sewing; Women; Individual Portraits; Syria; Photographic Prints
  - A woman operating a sewing machine, next Marie Rose Krikorian (left) who is wearing a headscarf (linked ref8,9)., Circa 1950-1965; 13 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Sewing; Group Portraits; Women
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (right) and a man seated at a table on a terrace., Circa 1940-1960; A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beyrouth (Beirut, Lebanon); 11.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Beirut, Lebanon; Drinks/Beverages; Fur Garments; Gloves; Restaurants/bars; Outdoors; Hats
  - Marie Rose Krikorian (center) seated at a table with Jareh Krikorian (left) and another man., Circa 1955-1970; 12.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Furnishings; Smoking; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Drinks/Beverages; Cigarettes; Restaurants/bars
  - A side profile of Marie Rose Krikorian and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1955-1970; 12.7 x 17.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Men; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A side profile of Marie Rose Krikorian wearing sunglasses in a vehicle., Circa 1950-1970; 11 x 17.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Syria; Individual Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A side profile of a woman., Circa 1950-1970; 13.1 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Syria; Individual Portraits
  - A portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian., Circa 1950-1970; 17.9 x 13.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Marie Rose Krikorian standing behind a child seated on a chair., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 6.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (center) standing with a multi-generational group in the middle of a street., Circa 1940-1960; 6.3 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; French Writing; Boys
  - A full-body portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian against a fabric backdrop., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children., Circa 1940-1960; 6.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Cameras; Individual Portraits; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (right) and a woman holding hands with a child., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 6.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Syria; Group Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (second from the right) with a multi-generational group in front of a tent., Circa 1940-1960; 6.2 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Tents; Children; Men; Group Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children beside a tree., Circa 1940-1960; 8.7 x 6.3 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Syria; French Writing; Signatures
  - A studio portrait of a man and a woman with a child., Circa 1940-1960; Dunia, Derhagopian, Rue Fouad, 1er, Damas (Damascus, Syria); 13.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Damascus, Syria; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing
  - A multi-generational group surrounding a table with two cakes., Circa 1940-1960; 6.1 x 8.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Women; Men; Children; Group Portraits; Syria; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Food; Parties; Girls; Boys; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - A studio portrait of a child sitting cross-legged., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 13.7 x 8.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Individual Portraits; Syria; Studio Photography; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing
  - Marie Rose Krikorian dancing with her husband, Jareh Krikorian (link ref28)., Circa 1955-1970; 17.9 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Dancing; Syria; Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian and Jareh Krikorian (link ref27)., Circa 1955-1970; 17.9 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Group Portraits; Men; Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dancing
  - A group portrait of individuals in two lines shaking hands, including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (center right)., Circa 1955-1970; 13.1 x 18.3 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Women
  - A multi-generational group gathered in a room, including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (center right)., Circa 1945-1965; 13 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Syria; Women; Children; Group Portraits; Men; Gatherings; Parties; Boys; Girls
  - A group of men and women dancing., Circa 1940-1970; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Syria; Dancing; Men; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A woman and man dancing, including Marie Rose Krikorian in the background (link ref32)., Circa 1940-1970; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Dancing; Syria; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A group portrait of a crowd., Circa 1950-1970; Studio Minas (Chouhada, Salhiyeh, Damascus, Syria); 13.1 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Damascus, Syria; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - Marie Rose Krikorian (right) seated with a multi-generational group at a table., June 1954; Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]; 13.2 x 18.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Group Portraits; Furnishings; Lebanon; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Drinks/Beverages; Restaurants/bars; Children
  - A woman and man dancing (link ref32)., Circa 1955-1970; 17.9 x 12.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Marie Rose Krikorian holding a baby to her face while seated., Circa 1940-1960; 6.1 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Syria; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (center right) at the baptism of her son., Circa 1940-1960; 6.1 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Women; Syria; Baptisms; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Gatherings; Children; Facial Hair; Boys
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (far right) at their child's baptism., Circa 1940-1960; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Baptisms; Girls; Women; Syria; Children; Religious Ceremony; Priests/Clergymen; Gatherings; Facial Hair; Events/Occasions; Religious Crosses; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Group Portraits
  - A group portrait of a priest carrying Marie Rose Krikorian's child at his baptism, with Marie in the background and Jareh on the far left., Circa 1940-1960; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Photographic Prints; Children; Baptisms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Syria; Women; Religious Ceremony; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair; Events/Occasions; Girls; Boys
  - A clergyman holding Marie Rose Krikorian's child during a baptism, including Marie on the left., Circa 1940-1960; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Men; Women; Baptisms; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Syria; Religious Ceremony; Gatherings; Children; Group Portraits; Events/Occasions; Facial Hair; Boys; Girls
  - A woman sitting by a door and holding a child., Circa 1940-1960; 9 x 6.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Syria; Children; Furnishings; Group Portraits
  - A portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian's child in a flower basinet before baptism., Circa 1940-1960; 8.9 x 6.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Individual Portraits; Baptisms; Syria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Children
  - Marie Rose Krikorian (center) bathing a child in a tub with a woman assisting., Circa 1940-1960; 11.2 x 6.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Children
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with two children., Circa 1940-1960; 6.2 x 8.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Children; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Syria; Boys
  - A group portrait of a clergyman baptizing a child standing in a tub. Jareh Krikorian stands off to the side., Circa 1940-1960; 6.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Group Portraits; Syria; Children; Baptisms; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Ceremony; Men; Girls; Books; Women; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Boys; Events/Occasions
  - A multi-generational group standing in front of five glass panels, including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (center)., Circa 1940-1960; 8.7 x 13.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Syria; Men; Women; Girls; Boys
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Syria; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Food; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a young child blowing candles on a cake., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.6 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Group Portraits; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Food; Men; Women; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 47, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Food; Syria; Furnishings; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Food; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gatherings; Parties; Group Portraits
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 47, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Children; Food; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food. (duplicate ref55, 54, 47, 50, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Children; Food; Women; Furnishings; Syria; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Furnishings; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Syria; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Food; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group portrait including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (top center)., Circa 1945-1965; 8.8 x 13.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Children; Syria; Men; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 52, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Food; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Food; Syria; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref52, 54, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Food; Syria; Children; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A man and a woman dancing amidst a crowd., Circa 1950-1970; 17.7 x 12.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Women; Syria; Men; Photographic Prints; Dancing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - A group portrait of three men and two women seated at a table., Circa 1950-1970; Photo Rapide, Grand Hotel Bloudan, Semerjdian Frères, [Syria]; 13.1 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Syria; Women; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hotels; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gatherings; Events/Occasions
  - A portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children., Circa 1950-1970; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 17.1 x 12.2 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Children; Boys; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Damascus, Syria; Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian seated at the head of a table with two men including Jareh Krikorian and two of her sons., Circa 1950-1975; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Women; Furnishings; Men; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Restaurants/bars; Boys; Children; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of three men and two women at a table including Marie Rose (left) and Jareh Krikorian (center)., Circa 1950-1975; 12.7 x 17.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Drinks/Beverages; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - Marie Rose Krikorian's son seated in between two other children on a pew., Circa 1950-1975; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 12.2 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Churches; Damascus, Syria; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Books; Religious Sites; Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gloves; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Arabic Writing
  - A portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian's son dressed in a bow tie., Circa 1950-1975; Studio Elias Hichmé, Bab-Touma, Damas, (Damascus, Syria); 17.3 x 12.2 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Damascus, Syria; Boys; Children; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (center) with a group of men and women at a table with Coca-Cola., Circa 1950-1975; 12.7 x 17.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Drinks/Beverages; Women; Men; Syria; Cigarettes; English Writing; Restaurants/bars; Arabic Writing
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian (center right) with officials of the Lebanese government., Circa 1940-1965; Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]; 13.2 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Cigarettes; Women; Men; Lebanon; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Officials; Events/Occasions; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Fur Garments; Drinks/Beverages; Smoking; Cigarettes; Facial Hair
  - Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian (far right) seated at a table with two other men., Circa 1945-1965; 12.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Food; Men; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose (center) and Jareh Krikorian (far left) with Mr. and Mrs. Ernesto Crespo., Circa 1945-1965; Studio Safar & Vartan, Rue Fardosse, Damas (Damascus, Syria); 12.9 x 17.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Women; Damascus, Syria; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait, including Marie Rose Krikorian (far left), at a meeting of the Armenian General Benevolent Union in Damascus., 1958; Garbis, Damas (Damascus, Syria); 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Food; Damascus, Syria; Women; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Armenian Writing
  - A group portrait of Mr. and Mrs. Krikorian with two men (left)., Circa 1945-1965; A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beyrouth (Beirut, Lebanon); 12.5 x 17.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Lebanon; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Fur Garments; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Smoking; Cigarettes